A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Program Related Investments (PRI), Economic Development Administration Program (EDA), Director, Office Files of Judith Samuelson FA727
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Program Related Investments (PRI), Economic Development Administration Program (EDA), Director, Office Files of Judith Samuelson
1988-1997
Rockefeller Archive Center
Samuelson, Judith F.
Ford Foundation
FA727
2.62 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains investment and development files.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Judith Samuelson joined the Ford Foundation in 1989 as Director of the Office of Program-Related Investments. In 1994 she helped launch the Foundation's Corporate Involvement Initiative, a program to substantially increase the involvement of corporations in community and economic development (CED). Samuelson left the Foundation in 1996 and became Executive Director of the Business and Society Program at the Aspen Institute in 1998.
- Social Investment Review (Box 1 (42617), Folder 1)
- Susan Berresford (Memos, Etc.), 1995 January 27 (Box 1 (42617), Folder 2)
- Baxter, Christie: Forward of Book, 1996 July (Box 1 (42617), Folder 3)
- Venzen Ross Consultancy: Interviews with Borrowers, 1995 (Box 1 (42617), Folder 4)
- Mission PRI (Box 1 (42617), Folder 5)
- PRI Publication (Box 1 (42617), Folder 6)
- Big Foundations/PRIs (Box 1 (42617), Folder 7)
- NP Capital Access Project (Box 1 (42617), Folder 8)
- Development Credit - Trustees Meeting/FF Policy (Box 1 (42617), Folder 9)
- Corporate Involvement - Internal FF Correspondence and collaboration (Box 1 (42617), Folder 10)
- Corporate Involvement - Phase I (Box 1 (42617), Folder 11)
- Corporate Involvement - Phase II (Box 1 (42617), Folder 12)
- FF Corporate Involvement Initiative (Box 1 (42617), Folder 13)
- Corporate Involvement - DCP, 1995 July (Box 1 (42617), Folder 14)
- CI: Global Citizenship (Box 1 (42617), Folder 15)
- Corporate Involvement - Ron Brown Award (Box 1 (42617), Folder 16)
- Corporate Involvement/Awards Program (contract) Economic and Social Research Institute (Box 1 (42617), Folder 17)
- Allen, Alice (Alice Allen Communications) (Box 2 (42618), Folder 1)
- Corporate Involvement - Welfare to Work (Box 2 (42618), Folder 2)
- Corporate Involvement Communications (Box 2 (42618), Folder 3)
- Corporate Involvement: Trustee Paper/Presentation, 1994 (Box 2 (42618), Folder 4)
- Economic and Social Research Institute (Box 2 (42618), Folder 5)
- Report: Potential Opportunities for Health Care Corporations to Affect Community Economic Development. Prepared for the Ford Foundation Corporate Involvement Task Force. Cynthia Orbovich, Ph.D. Consultant, 1996 September (Box 2 (42618), Folder 6)
- Report, Unpublished: Nonprofit Community Accessibility to Financing in New York City. Frank Di Giovanni. Consultant (Box 2 (42618), Folder 7)